

□+1 516-859-6058 | ■ anagi202@gmail.com | 🖷 alinagi.com | 🖸 anagi202 | 🛅 ali-nagi

## Summary\_

Ali is a high-energy, outspoken designer and engineer with a passion for creating beautiful, frictionless experiences. He enjoys talking to people and iterating on new ideas. He looks forward to impactful work and meaningful contributions.

# **Public Projects**

2018 **nexen.bnymellon.com**, Developed common components for unified business platform

2017 **developer.bnymellon.com**, Part of the engineering team to build BNY Mellon's first developer site

2017 **Pie Storm**, A humble attempt to gamify charitable donations

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

BNY Mellon Jersey City, NJ

#### DESIGNER / FULL-STACK ENGINEER- USER EXPERIENCE TEAM

June 2017 - Present

- Design and develop an internal Material Design-based UI component library in Angular 2+ for use by hundreds of developers.
- Migrate existing UI components from Angular.js to Angular 2+.
- Create 10+ business-facing prototypes using Axure RP and Sketch.
- Conduct client-facing user-interaction research using in-house UX lab.
- Implement and deploy RESTful APIs in Python (Flask) and Go.

BNY Mellon Jersey City, NJ

#### ASSOCIATE - TECHNOLOGY LEADERSHIP PROGRAM

June 2016 - June 2017

- Database-as-a-Service: Automated secure MongoDB deployment on BNY Mellon's internal cloud for use by development teams.
- Developer Console: Full-stack Go + Angular development of a developer-facing web app.
- · User Experience: Designed Angular.js components and implemented with full Karma test coverage.

BNY Mellon Jersey City, NJ

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER - USER EXPERIENCE TEAM

June - August, 2014 - 2016

- · Utilized Phaser HTML5 game engine to create an internal educational game for employees to learn about concepts such as RESTful APIs.
- Deployed educational game to internal cloud platform for testing by early user group.

#### The Polytechnic Reporter

New York, NY

#### **EXECUTIVE EDITOR AND DESIGNER**

August 2013 - May 2016

- Served as final editor for newspaper with circulation in the thousands.
- Designed and published layouts for staff writers using Adobe InDesign.

### Skills\_

**Programming** Python, Go, JavaScript, TypeScript

**Front-end** Angular, Angular-Material, NPM, Bower, WebPack, Bootstrap

**UX + Design** Axure, Sketch, GIMP, Adobe Suite

Mobile Android, Flutter

## **Education**

#### **New York University**

New York, New York

**B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE** 

August 2012 - May 2016

### Interests

**Hobbies** Physical fitness, hiking, drawing

**Passions** High-quality designs, blending art and engineering